Kyle Downey

Front-End Web Developer

Oak Lawn, IL

github.com/kylefdowney (708) 710-3471

kylefdowney@gmail.com

Summary

I am a proficient Front-End Developer with experience building hands-on applications using languages like React and Angular.

Skills

Web Development

HTML / CSS, JavaScript, React, Angular, jQuery, Bootstrap, Git, APIs, SQL, Python, Django

User Experience Design

Responsive Design, Wireframes, Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign, After Effects

Education

Chicago Coding Temple

2017

Accelerated course on JavaScript, Angular, ¡Query, Python, HTML5, CSS3, Web Api's, & Bootstrap UI

Illinois State University

2015 - 2017

Bachelor of Science in Arts Technology – 3.7 GPA

Professional Experience

Podverse 2020

Intern

- Performed quality assurance testing on React and React Native apps, across iOS, Android, & Web.
- Updated and maintained the database to add new podcasts as requested by users.

Garfield Building Maintenance

2019 - 2020

Webmaster

- Designed and programmed a new responsive static website for Garfield Building Maintenance.
- Managed the domain registration and handled deployment of the new website.

Weaver Consultants Group

2018

Software Support Specialist

- Developed a PHP web app to analyze readings and data-trends from excel files containing site data.
- Assisted coworkers from all departments in computer and Active Directory related troubleshooting.

ISU's College of Arts and Sciences IT

2016 - 2017

Web Developer / Project Manager

- Managed the development of new and existing university websites and their features.
- Led new employees on onboarding procedures and designated tasks.

Portfolio

Video Game Portal

A responsive web app built with React, populated with data from the world's largest video game API.

- Demo: kylefdowney.github.io/GameAPI/
- Repo: github.com/kylefdowney/GameAPI

Various Projects

- Demo: kylefdowney.github.io/kfdportfolio
- Repo: github.com/kylefdowney/kfdportfolio